Finding Aid for Ann Arbor Junior Chamber of Commerce records, 1936-1985
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Ann Arbor Junior Chamber of Commerce records
1936-1985
Ann Arbor Junior Chamber of Commerce (Mich.)
8537 Bm 2; Bm Outsize
Ann Arbor chapter of the Junior Chamber of Commerce, a young adult community service organization; minutes, project files, budgets, newsletters, photographs, and related material.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
14.3 linear feet
1 oversize folders
The bulk of the records came from the organization (donor no. 6628 ); other materials came from Katherine Simon Smith (donor no. 5234 ).
No further additions to the records are expected.
The collection is open to research.
The United States Junior Chamber (Jaycees) (according to its website) "gives young people between the ages of 18 and 40 the tools they need to build the bridges of success for themselves in the areas of business development, management skills, individual training, community service and international connections." The Ann Arbor Junior Chamber of Commerce was organized in 1935
The record group consists of seven series: Administrative Files, Projects, Auxiliary, Topical Files, Publications, State and Local Jaycees, and Other Materials.
Subjects:
Ann Arbor Junior Chamber of Commerce (Mich.); Social service--Michigan--Ann Arbor--Societies, etc.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
African Americans--Women.; Ann Arbor Junior Chamber of Commerce (Mich.); Clowns.; Community service.; Fund raising.; Pumpkins.; War bonds and funds.; World War, 1939-1945.
Genre Terms:
Motion pictures.; Photographs.
- Administrative Files
  The Administrative Files series documents the Ann Arbor Junior Chamber of Commerce's organizational functions including: executive meetings, finances, membership administration, and correspondence.
  - Articles of incorporation (Box 1)
  - Constitution and By-Laws, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - By-laws, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Annual Report, 1938-1939 (Box 1)
  - Non-Profit Corporation Annual Reports (Box 1)
  - Board of Directors meetings minutes
    - 1961-1962 (Box 1)
    - 1963-1966 (Box 1)
    - 1967-1972, 1980 (Box 1)
    - 1974-1975 (Box 1)
  - Notebook with minutes, budgets, and newsletters, 1961-1962 (Box 1)
  - Notebook including minutes, newsletters, and financial, 1964-1965 (Box 1)
  - Financial material, 1960s (Box 1)
  - Financial notebook, 1963-1964 (Box 1)
  - Planned year's programs and budgets, 1960s (Box 1)
  - Planned Year's Programs and budgets
    - 1966-1972 (Box 1)
    - 1972-1978 (Box 1)
  - Budget and accounts, 1972-1973 (Box 1)
  - Treasurer's reports, 1970-1971 (Box 1)
  - Elections, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Papers of officers
    - President Edward L. Barnard (Box 1)
    - President Thomas E. Bletcher (Box 1)
    - Director Jack Limmer (notebook) (Box 1)
  - Correspondence and other papers
    - 1939-1942 (Box 1)
    - 1943 (Box 1)
    - 1944 (Box 2)
    - 1958-1962 (Box 2)
    - 1963-1965 (Box 2)
    - 1966-1967 (Box 2)
    - 1968-1971 (Box 2)
    - 1972-1980 (Box 2)
  - Notebook containing photographs, newsletters and miscellanea, 1964-1965 (Box 2)
  - External Programming Notebook, 1973 (Box 2)
    (community relations, ecology, etc.)
  - Internal Programming Notebook, 1974 (Box 2)
    (membership, leadership, communication, etc.)
  - Membership manuals
    - 1968 (Box 2)
    - 1970-1971 (Box 2)
  - Membership material, 1960s (Box 2)
  - Membership, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Membership manuals, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - History, 1930s (Box 2)
- Projects
  The Projects series documents the various initiatives the organization was involved with, showing their diverse range of activities.
  - Agriculture and conservation (Box 3)
  - Americanism (Box 3)
  - Chapter activities (Box 3)
  - Chapter development (Box 3)
  - Chapter management (Box 3)
  - Civic and community improvement (Box 4)
  - Community action (Box 4)
  - Community health and safety (Box 4)
  - Education (Box 4)
  - Environment (Box 5)
  - Giessenbier Memorial Award (Box 5)
  - Governmental (Box 6)
  - Human relations (Box 6)
  - Inner city (Box 6)
  - Inter-club relations (Box 6)
  - Internal affairs (Box 7)
  - International (Box 7)
  - Jaycees for handicapped children (Box 7)
  - Membership (Box 7)
  - Public affairs (Box 7)
  - Public relations (Box 7)
  - Publications (Box 7)
  - Publications (cont.) (Box 8)
  - Recreation and sports (Box 8)
  - Religious and Christmas (Box 8)
  - Senior citizens (Box 8)
  - Unemployment and retraining (Box 8)
  - Ways and means (Box 8)
  - Ways and means (cont.) (Box 9)
  - Welfare (Box 9)
  - Youth and Sports (Box 9)
  - Soap Box Derby, 1963-1964; 1965 (Box 9)
  - Builders Show (Box 9)
  - Community development (Box 9)
  - Records and Recognition
    - International apprenticeship (Box 9)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 9)
  - Seat-belt promotion (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous, 1963-1976; 3 folders (Box 9)
- Auxiliary
  The Auxiliary was the women's branch of the Chamber of Commerce when the latter was only for men. Since the organization is now co-ed, the Auxiliary no longer exists.
  - Minutes of meetings and agendas
    - 1964-1965 (Box 9)
    - 1966-1967 (Box 9)
    - 1967-1968 (Box 9)
    - 1968-1970 (Box 9)
    - 1971-1979 (Box 9)
  - Annual report, 1968-1969 (Box 9)
  - Budgets and financial reports, 1963-1970 (Box 9)
  - Activities and finances, 1970-1971 (Box 9)
  - Notebooks of minutes, finances, and activities
    - 1967-1968 (Box 9)
    - 1968-1969 (Box 9)
    - 1969-1970 (Box 10)
  - Constitutional Revision Committee (Box 10)
  - Reports of activities, 1967-1968 (Box 10)
  - Extension, 1963-1964 (Box 10)
  - Newsletters, 1968-1970 (Box 10)
  - Membership (Box 10)
  - Membership manuals
    - 1964 (Box 10)
    - 1968 (Box 10)
  - Christmas shopping tour and party, 1964 (Box 10)
  - Charter Night, 1964 (Box 10)
  - Scholarships, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Records and recognition (Box 10)
  - Award entries
    - Jaycee assistance (Box 10)
    - M.O.R. (Box 10)
    - Outstanding Presidents Award (Box 10)
    - Ways and Means (Box 10)
    - Community service (Box 10)
  - Projects
    - Four Outstanding Young Women, 1966-1967; 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Michigan Association for Emotionally Disturbed Children, 1964 (Box 11)
    - Assisting Jaycees (Box 11)
    - Community service (Box 11)
    - Money-making (Box 11)
    - Social (Box 11)
    - Miscellaneous projects, 1960-1970; 7 folders (Box 11)
  - Edith Bletcher correspondence (Box 11)
  - General information (Box 11)
  - Miscellaneous, 1962-1963 (Box 11)
  - Miscellaneous, 1964-1969 (Box 11)
- Topical Files
  The Topical Files documents various other initiatives and projects of the organization that were not substantial enough to be included in the other series. It also includes information on the awards and recognition honors bestowed by the Chamber of Commerce.
  - Award entries
    - Americanism and governmental affairs (Box 12)
    - Inter-club relations and extensions (Box 12)
    - International relations (Box 12)
    - Ways and means (Box 12)
    - Youth and sports activities (Box 12)
  - Ann Arbor
    - High School racial problems, 1960s (Box 12)
    - Human Relations Commission minutes
      - 1957 (Box 12)
      - 1958 (Box 12)
      - 1959 (Box 12)
      - 1960-1965 (Box 12)
  - "Basic Guide to Public Relations in Project Planning,", 1972 (Box 12)
  - Banquets, dinners, dances (Box 12)
  - Bid for National Convention, 1985 (Box 12)
  - Bosses Night, 1974 (Box 12)
  - Campaign of Ann Arbor Jaycees President, 1974 (Box 12)
  - Community Development Survey, 1961-1962 (Box 12)
  - Distinguished Service Awards
    - 1965-1966, 4 folders (Box 12)
  - Events calendars (Box 12)
  - Family Life Development (Box 12)
  - Fourth of July Fireworks, 1982-1985; 3 folders (Box 12)
  - Freedom Guard, 1972 (Box 12)
  - Geddes Lake Improvement Association (Box 12)
  - Huron River Watershed Intergovernmental Committee, 1963 (Box 12)
  - Installation Dinner Dance, 1978 (Box 12)
  - Insurance (Box 12)
  - Manual for Chairman (Box 12)
  - Manual for City Beautification Committee, 1940 (Box 12)
  - Metro-Detroit meetings (Box 12)
  - Mid-America Institute Convention in Ann Arbor, 1967 (Box 12)
  - Miss Ann Arbor Pageant, 1969 (Box 12)
  - National Convention Committee, 1971-1972; 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Operation Literacy, 1963 (Box 12)
  - Orientation (Box 13)
  - Polio Immunization Survey of the Mitchell School District, 1959 (Box 13)
  - Political protest-miscellaneous (Box 13)
  - Records and Recognition
    - Objectives, 1964-1965 (Box 13)
    - Community Recognition Night, 1966 (Box 13)
    - Soap Box Derby, 1967 (Box 13)
    - State Softball Tournament, 1972 (Box 13)
    - New Citizens Award, 1972 (Box 13)
    - R and R Manual (Box 13)
    - Miscellaneous, 1971-1972 (Box 13)
  - Scrapbook, 1963-1964 (Box 13)
  - Spirit of '76 Committee (Box 13)
  - State Junior Tennis Tournament, 1959 (Box 13)
  - "Ten True Stories Taken from Case Records," Ann Arbor Community Fund, 1937-1941 (Box 13)
  - Washtenaw County Citizens' Committee for Economic Opportunity (Box 13)
  - Women's movement (Box 13)
  - World War II (Miscellaneous) (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 13)
- Publications
  Various newsletters can be found in the Publications series, from the president's (Simon Sez) to the organization's own newsletters and bulletins.
  - President's Newsletters (Simon Sez), 1963-1964 (Box 13)
  - Ann Arbor Jaycee News, 1965 (Box 13)
  - News Flashes, 1965-1966 (Box 13)
  - Newsletters, 1967-1972; 4 folders (Box 13)
- State and Local Jaycees
  The State and Local Jaycees documents some of the activities of the larger chapter's administration and other local chapters' projects and administration.
  - Michigan Jaycees
    - By-laws and Policy (Box 13)
    - Executive Committee and Board of Directors' minutes of meetings and agendas
      - 1960s (Box 13)
      - 1971-1972 (Box 13)
    - Finances, 1965; 1966; 1971-1972 (Box 13)
    - Activation and Involvement Manual (Box 13)
    - Awards Manual (Box 13)
    - Chapter Manual (Box 13)
    - External Area Project Handbook, 1967-1968 (Box 13)
    - State conventions and meetings, 1960s (Box 13)
    - National convention, 1968 (Box 13)
    - President's memoranda (Box 13)
    - Officers, 1965-1966 (Box 13)
    - Governmental Affairs Gab Editor's correspondence, 1965 (Box 13)
    - Jaycee Michigander materials (Box 13)
    - Policy motions, 1957 (Box 13)
    - Auxiliary
      - M.J.A. Keystone, 1968-1971 (Box 14)
      - Meetings and newsletters, 2 folders (Box 14)
      - Yearbook, 1966-1967 (Box 14)
      - Miscellaneous, 4 folders (Box 14)
    - Five Outstanding Young Men (Box 14)
    - Hotline (newsletters), 1965-1972 (Box 14)
    - Mock legislature, 1964 (Box 14)
    - War Conference, 1943 (Box 14)
    - Miscellaneous papers, 1973-1975 (Box 14)
  - Local chapters
    - Ypsilanti Jaycees Membership Manual (Box 14)
    - District 5 (later District 26) material (Box 14)
    - Projects of various local chapters, 1939-1942 (Box 14)
    - Misc. newsletters of local chapters (Box 14)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 14)
- Other materials
  The Other Materials series includes a scattering of photographs, a motion picture, scrapbooks of clippings and other documents relating to the work of the Ann Arbor chapter during World War II.
  - Photographs and film of the organizations and its activities, 5 folders (Box 14)
  - Scrapbook concerning War Services Projects, 1941-1942 (Box 15)
  - Scrapbook concerning War Services Projects, 1942-1943 (Box 15)
  - Fireworks poster (Folder Bm)
  - Charter, 1936 (Folder Bm)